BEN KEMPENICH

Irvine, CA | (562) 256-6070 | Benkemp@uci.edu | Linkedin/in/benkempenich

INVESTMENT PROFESSIONAL

Eight years of experience in the financial services industry with expertise in equity research, bank operations, investments, and business development. Strong analytical, problem solving, and communication skills with indepth knowledge of financial modeling, forecasting, and business strategy.

EXPERIENCE

AMERIGO CAPITAL, Newport Beach, CA

10/2016 - present

Private Equity Analyst

Responsible for buy side processes including potential acquisition screening, initial outreach, due diligence, financial modeling, and presentation development.

THE INNOVATION INSTITUTE, Newport Beach, CA

04/2016 - 8/2016

Investment Banking Analyst

Worked directly with the Chief Investment Officer and participated in the design, execution, and marketing of \$150m investment funds targeting healthcare related innovation.

- Analyzed and performed due diligence on acquisition candidates including financial forecast models, industry analysis, and benchmarking against similar companies which contributed to C-level decisions.
- Co-authored multiple articles focused on healthcare related innovation and impact investing which were published in widely distributed financial and investment news sites.

ROTH CAPITAL PARTNERS, LLC, Irvine, CA

06/2015 - 12/2015

Equity Research MBA Intern

Performed sell-side equity research focused on clean tech and industrial small-cap stocks at a boutique investment bank.

- Maintained market intelligence system and provided ongoing monitoring of companies in the Cleantech and Industrial sectors involving analysis of micro and macro-economic trends.
- Developed full circle financial models and conducted financial statement analysis to forecast income statements, balance sheets, and cash flows.
- Performed primary and secondary research and preparation of comprehensive research notes for distribution to institutional clients including an initiation report for a recent IPO.

JPMORGAN CHASE, Redondo Beach, CA

06/2009 - 08/2014

Operations Officer (07/2013 - 08/2014)

Co-managed 5-10 people in operations and sales in new build branches including coaching and maintaining operational metrics.

- Ensured two satisfactory operations audits in recently opened branches by training staff in cash and negotiable instrument controls and regulatory compliance.
- Coached staff on maintaining and troubleshooting clients' information security, account opening activities, and policies and procedures.

Licensed Personal Banker (06/2009 - 07/2013)

Established, maintained, and grew relationships with clients. Assessed financial needs and offered a variety of financial services and investment opportunities including mortgages, premium products for high net worth clients, and mutual funds.

- #1 in District sales production in January, July and September 2012. Consistently highly ranked among bankers for production volume.
- Obtained Series 6, Series 63, and Variable Life licenses in 2011.

BEN KEMPENICH PAGE 2

P&C FINANCIAL AND INSURANCE SERVICES, INC., Irvine, CA

09/2008 - 02/2009

Executive Assistant

Provided information management and marketing support, including compiling research on stocks, insurance products, and sales prospects for a start-up insurance and investment business.

- Improved inter-office communication by getting management buy-in and implementing a cloud-based office collaborative system.
- Spearheaded and marketed a webinar series given by a local expert on retirement products.

MULTI-SERVICES, INC., Portland, OR

09/2007 - 05/2008

Concierge

Provided quality concierge services to residents of newly built luxury condominium high-rise.

FRED MEYER, INC., Portland, OR

03/2006 - 09/2007

Front Information Desk (03/2006 - 09/2007)

• Received three promotions in twelve months.

PORTLAND BOLT CO.

07/2004 - 11/2005

Inside Sales/ Cost Estimator

EDUCATION

University of California, Irvine, The Paul Merage School of Business, Irvine, CA

06/2016

Master of Business Administration, Finance & Strategy

- Best negotiation, 2016 UCI Technology and Entrepreneurship Competition
- ACG Cup Corporate Valuation Case Competition
- Quantitative coursework and case project experience in accounting, investments, corporate valuation, venture capital, private equity, risk management, and business strategy.

California State University, Long Beach, Long Beach, CA

09/2012

Economics, Post-Graduate Study

The College of Idaho, Caldwell, ID

06/2004

Bachelor of Music

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS/LEADERSHIP

UCI eSports – Board of Advisors

• Advising on strategy for the upcoming gaming center and eSports arena.

Merage Student Association – Vice President, Finance

UCI Challenge for Charity - Vice President, Finance